Guide to the Hans Caspar Syz Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Writings and Research Materials, 1911-1987, undated; Series III
  - Published
    - Articles
      - "Two modes of Social Adaptation and their Concomitants in Ocular Movements," The Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology, Vol. 44, No. 2 [reprint], 1949 (Box 43, Folder 37)
      - "Studies with the Lifwynn Eye-Movement Camera," Journal of the Biological Photographic Association [reprint], 1949 (Box 43, Folder 38)
      - "New Perspectives in Behavior Study: A Phylobiological Reorientation," The Journal of Psychology, Vol. 31 [reprint], 1951 (Box 43, Folder 39)
      - "Our Common Prejudice," [notes], 1951 (Box 43, Folder 40)
      - "An Experiment in Inclusive Psychotherapy," Experimental Psychopathology [reprint], 1954-1957 (Box 43, Folder 41)
      - "Phylobiological Research," Views and Ideas of Mankind [reprints], 1957 (Box 43, Folder 42)
      - "Trigant Burrow's Thesis in Relation to Psychotherapy," Progress in Psychotherapy [reprint], 1957 (Box 43, Folder 43)
      - "Problems of Perspective against the Background of Trigant Burrow's Group-analytic Researches," The International Journal of Group Psychotherapy, Vol. XI, No. 2 [notes and reprint], 1961 (Box 43, Folder 44)
      - "A Summary Note on the Work of Trigant Burrow," The International Journal of Social Psychiatry, Vol. VII, No. 4 [notes and reprint], 1961 (Box 43, Folder 45)
      - "Reflections on Group- or Phylo- Analysis," Acta Psychotherapeutica, supplemental ad, Vol. 11 [reprint], 1963 (Box 43, Folder 46)
      - "Value Problems in Psychotherapy against the Background of Trigant Burrow's Group Analysis," Historical Explorations in Medicine and Psychiatry (H. Riese, Ed.), 1978 (Box 43, Folder 46)
        - Notes, Undated (Box 43, Folder 47)
        - Drafts, Undated (Box 43, Folder 48-51)
        - Reprint, 1978 (Box 43, Folder 52)
    - Books
      - Vom Sein und vom Sinn, 1972
        - German notes [original and transcript], 1916 (Box 44, Folder 53-54)
        - English translation of original notes, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 55)
        - Notes on original notes, 1969-1971 (Box 44, Folder 56)
        - Critique by Iris (Ciarpella) Gelletti, Circa 1972 (Box 44, Folder 57)
        - Publication information, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 58)
        - Proof, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 59)
        - Published version (Zürich: Editio Academica), 1972 (Box 44, Folder 60)
      - Of Being and of Meaning [translation of Vom Sein und 61 Vom Sinn by B. Merker], 1981 (Box 44, Folder 60)
        - Preface, 1969 (Box 44, Folder 61)
        - Publication information, Circa 1979-1980 (Box 44, Folder 62)
        - Published version (New York: Philosophical Library), 1981 (Box 44, Folder 63)
        - Correspondence concerning Vom Sein und vom Sinn and Of Being and of Meaning, 1973-1985 (Box 44, Folder 64-68)
        - Records of receipt of complimentary library copies of Vom Sein und vom Sinn and Of Being and of Meaning, 1972-1982 (Box 44, Folder 69-71)
        - Reviews of and Vom Sein und vom Sinn and Of Being and of Meaning, 1972-1987 (Box 45, Folder 72)
    - Reviews
      - " The A-B-C of Aesthetics by Leo Stein,", 1927 (Box 45, Folder 73)
      - "A Review of The Social Basis of Consciousness: A Study in Organic Psychology based upon a Synthetic and Societal Concept of the Neuroses ", 1928 (Box 45, Folder 74)
      - "The `Social Neurosis' [by Trigant Burrow], 1937 (Box 45, Folder 75)
      - " The Biology of Human Conflict - An Anatomy of Behavior Individual and Social by Trigant Burrow ," [for Mental Hygiene ], 1938
        - Notes and drafts, 1937 (Box 45, Folder 76)
        - Typescript and reprint, 1937-1938 (Box 45, Folder 77)
      - "Trigant Burrow: The Biology of Human Conflict ", Journal of Social Philosophy, 1938 (Box 45, Folder 78)
      - "`The Neurodynamics of Behavior'. A Phylobiological Foreword by Trigant Burrow, M.D., Ph.D.", 1946 (Box 45, Folder 79)
      - " The Neurosis of Man - An Introduction to a Science of Human Behavior by Trigant Burrow, M.D.", 1951
        - Notes, 1946-1951 (Box 45, Folder 80)
        - Notes and reprint, Circa 1951 (Box 45, Folder 81)
      - " Education Through Art, by Herbert Read," [notes and reprint], 1947 (Box 45, Folder 82)
        box 11, folder 238-239
      - " Conceptions of Disease, its History, its Versions and its Nature, by Walther Riese", 1953 (Box 45, Folder 83)
      - " Our Common Neurosis; Notes on a Group Experiment, by Charles B. Thompson and Alfreda P. Sill," [notes and reprint], 1954 (Box 45, Folder 84)
      - " Science and Man's Behavior: The Contribution of Phylobiology, by Trigant Burrow, M.D., Ph.D.," [notes, drafts and typescript], 1953-1954 (Box 45, Folder 85)
      - " A History of Neurology, by Walther Riese," [notes and reprint], 1960 (Box 45, Folder 86)
      - " Galen: On the Passions and Errors of the Soul. With an Introduction and Interpretation by Walther Riese." [reprint], 1966 (Box 45, Folder 87)
      - "Discussion of Dr. Srole's Paper," [reprint], 1968 (Box 45, Folder 88)
  - Unpublished writings
    - General
      - Paper topics, 1927-1966, undated (Box 45, Folder 89-94)
      - Abstracts prepared for conferences, 1951-1960, undated (Box 45, Folder 95-96)
      - Contents of 'black binders' [index of Syz's personal collection of his unpublished writings], 1977 (Box 45, Folder 97)
    - Articles, books and book reviews
      - Acta paper
        - Notes, 1962 (Box 45, Folder 98)
        - Outline of section IV, 1962 (Box 45, Folder 99-100)
      - "Altered Criteria"
        - Notes, 1941-1943 (Box 46, Folder 101)
        - Typescript, 1943-1945 (Box 46, Folder 102-103)
      - Altered perspective, 1947 (Box 46, Folder 104-106)
      - "Annotations"
        - Draft, 1971-1976 (Box 46, Folder 107-109)
        - Typescript, 1971-1976 (Box 46, Folder 110-111)
      - Applications
        - Notes, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 112)
        - Sections
          - "Individual psychology,", 1929-1933 (Box 46, Folder 113)
          - "Mental hygiene,", 1930-1932 (Box 46, Folder 114)
          - "Psychoanalysis"
            - Notes and material, 1923-1933 (Box 46, Folder 115)
            - Drafts, 1924-1933 (Box 46, Folder 116)
          - "Psychiatric Theories,", 1931-1933 (Box 46, Folder 117)
          - "Social Approach"
            - Notes, 1927 (Box 46, Folder 118)
            - Draft, Circa 1927 (Box 46, Folder 119)
          - "Social Psychiatry,", 1918-1933 (Box 46, Folder 120)
          - "Sociological Data,", Circa 1931-1934, 1952 (Box 46, Folder 121-123)
        - Draft, 1932 (Box 46, Folder 124)
      - Archaeological paper, 1938 (Box 47, Folder 125)
      - "Aspects of the Guilt Reaction in Normal and Disordered States" [Guilt paper]
        - Material, 1931 (Box 47, Folder 126)
        - Notes, 1931 (Box 47, Folder 127)
        - Drafts, Circa 1931 (Box 47, Folder 128-129)
        - Typescript [read in outline at the Eighty-Seventh Annual Meeting of the American Psychiatric Association], 1931 (Box 47, Folder 130)
        - Typescript, 1933 (Box 47, Folder 131)
        - German translation ["Phasen der Schuldreaktion…"], Undated (Box 47, Folder 132)
      - "Basic Awareness and Being"
        box 15, folder 1-5
        box 24, folder 222-224
        - Early notes, 1916-1918 (Box 47, Folder 133)
        - Later notes, 1972-1976 (Box 47, Folder 134)
        - Draft, 1969-1971 (Box 47, Folder 135-140)
        - Critique by Iris (Ciarpella) Gelletti, 1972 (Box 47, Folder 141)
        - Revision by Alfreda S. Galt, Undated (Box 47, Folder 142-143)
      - Basic principles
        - Notes, 1978-1980 (Box 47, Folder 144)
        - Drafts, 1979-1980 (Box 47, Folder 145)
      - Basic reorientation
        - Notes, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 146)
        - Drafts, 1949 (Box 47, Folder 147)
      - "Biological Criteria", 1941-1944 (Box 47, Folder 148)
      - "Biological Principles"
        - Reference material, 1934 (Box 48, Folder 149)
        - Notes, 1934 (Box 48, Folder 150-154)
        - Outline, 1934 (Box 48, Folder 155)
        - Drafts, 1934 (Box 48, Folder 156-170)
      - "A Brief Report" [presented at New Haven, CT], 1964 (Box 49, Folder 171)
        box 5, folder 92-94
      - Bull paper, 1962
        box 52, folder 278-280
      - Burrow's early papers [draft 5], 1932 (Box 49, Folder 172)
      - "Burrow's Phylopathological Investigations in Relation to Behavior Disorders" [Diethelm paper]
        - Notes, 1939 (Box 49, Folder 173)
        - Drafts 1-3, 1939 (Box 49, Folder 174-176)
        - Typescript presented at staff meeting of Payne Whitney Clinic, New York Hospital, 1939 (Box 49, Folder 177)
        - Typescript (Box 49, Folder 178)
        - German translation ["Burrows phylopathologische Untersuchuungen…"], 1929, 1939 (Box 49, Folder 179-180)
      - Collected papers of Trigant Burrow [outline], 1933 (Box 49, Folder 181)
      - "Compilation of five papers by Trigant Burrow", 1944 (Box 49, Folder 182)
      - Democracy paper [notes and material], 1939 (Box 49, Folder 183)
      - "The Dependence-reaction in its Relation to Behavior Disorders" [Dependence Reaction, paper read at the Twenty-seventh Annual Meeting of the American Psychopathological Association], 1937
        - Notes, 1936 (Box 49, Folder 184)
        - Outline, 1936 (Box 49, Folder 185)
        - Drafts 1-4, 1936 (Box 49, Folder 186)
        - Submitted typescript, 1937 (Box 49, Folder 187)
        - Revision, 1938 (Box 49, Folder 188)
      - Diethelm paper, 1939
        box 43, folder 32
      - "Discussion of Dr. Burrow's paper" [read in San Francisco], 1938 (Box 49, Folder 189)
      - "Discussion of Burrow's 'The problem of the self in relation to group therapy'" [paper read at a meeting of the American Psychopathological Association], 1944 (Box 49, Folder 190)
    - "Discussion of Milton Erickson's paper", 1929, 1939 (Box 49, Folder 191-192)
      - Early essays, 1911 (Box 49, Folder 193)
      - "Experimental Frustration in a Group of Hominids"
        box 51, folder 255-256
        - Notes, 1940 (Box 49, Folder 194)
        - Drafts and presented typescript, 1940 (Box 49, Folder 195)
      - Experimental notes [self-observation], Circa 1935-1936 (Box 49, Folder 196)
      - Experimental observations
        - Self-observation, 1934 (Box 49, Folder 197)
        - Drafts, Circa 1937-1938 (Box 49, Folder 198)
      - Experimental possibilities [notes], 1937-1947 (Box 49, Folder 199)
      - "Experimental Procedures Employed in Psychopathology", 1926 (Box 50, Folder 200)
      - Experimental problems [notes], 1938 (Box 50, Folder 201)
      - Experimental tensions [notes, self-observation], 1934-1938 (Box 50, Folder 202-203)
      - Experiments with the psychogalvanic reflex [notes] (Box 50, Folder 204)
      - Freud, Undated (Box 50, Folder 205)
      - Galdston paper
        box 48, folder 170
      - General principles, 1934-1979 (Box 50, Folder 206)
      - Group therapy [notes], 1944 (Box 50, Folder 207)
      - Guilt paper, 1931
        box 47, folder 125-130
      - Gutkind material, 1937 (Box 50, Folder 208)
      - Human characteristics, Circa 1967 (Box 50, Folder 209)
      - Image
        - Excerpts, 1932 (Box 50, Folder 210)
        - Notes, 1933-1934 (Box 50, Folder 211-212)
        - Drafts, 1932-1934 (Box 50, Folder 213)
      - Instrumental experimentation [descriptions of research equipment used by the Lifwynn Foundation], 1964-1966 (Box 50, Folder 214)
      - Integration, Circa 1926 (Box 50, Folder 215)
      - Integration against statistics, Circa 1926-1927 (Box 50, Folder 216)
      - Introduction, 1942 (Box 50, Folder 217)
      - Introduction to phylopathology, 1941 (Box 50, Folder 218)
      - Jaatinen case, 1936
        box 42, folder 13-17
        box 78, folder 26-28
      - "Kymograph records…" [review of paper by Trigant Burrow], 1938 (Box 50, Folder 219)
      - Lecture on psychological processes, 1926 (Box 50, Folder 220)
      - Miscellaneous essays, 1947-1948 (Box 50, Folder 221)
      - "Monograph" [an analysis of the material on which Of Being and of Meaning is based]
        - Draft, 1971-1973 (Box 50, Folder 222-224)
        - Typescript, Circa 1971-1973 (Box 50, Folder 225-226)
      - "Next Development in Man" [notes for review of book by L.L. Whyte], 1949 (Box 50, Folder 227-228)
      - "Our Common Prejudice"
        - Notes, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 229)
        - Draft, 1951 (Box 50, Folder 230)
      - "Paranoid constellation, or a preface to phylopathology", 1949 (Box 51, Folder 231)
      - Personality study
        - Data, 1925-1926, undated (Box 51, Folder 232)
        - Typescript, 1931-1939 (Box 51, Folder 233)
      - Phyloanalysis [excerpts], Undated (Box 51, Folder 234)
      - "Phylobiology and phylopathology: Discussion of various features", 1944 (Box 51, Folder 235)
      - "Phylobiology or -pathology"
        - Outline, 1944 (Box 51, Folder 236)
        - Book typescript, 1944 (Box 51, Folder 237-238)
      - "Phylopathology"
        - Notes, 1933-1934, undated (Box 51, Folder 239-240)
        - Draft of outline, 1933 (Box 51, Folder 241)
        - Material and notes, Circa 1936 (Box 51, Folder 242-243)
        - Notes for introduction, 1936 (Box 51, Folder 244)
        - Drafts of introduction, 1936 (Box 51, Folder 245)
        - Chapters
          - Chapter 1, first draft, 1936 (Box 51, Folder 246)
          - Chapter 1, second draft, Circa 1936 (Box 51, Folder 247)
          - Chapter 2, Circa 1936 (Box 51, Folder 248)
          - Chapter 4, 5 "Tensional patterns", Circa 1936 (Box 51, Folder 249)
        - Source material [clippings and reprints], 1938-1944 (Box 51, Folder 250)
        - Case material, 1941 (Box 51, Folder 251)
        - Typescript, 1941 (Box 51, Folder 252)
        - Book outline, 1944-1946 (Box 51, Folder 253)
      - Phylopathology and psychiatry, 1941 (Box 51, Folder 254)
      - "Physiological Aspects of Different Adaptive Orientations", 1938 (Box 51, Folder 255-256)
      - "Problem of the Self" [review of paper by Trigant Burrow], 1944 (Box 51, Folder 257)
      - "Psychiatry as a Social Science" [review of paper by Zilboorg], 1942 (Box 51, Folder 258)
      - Psychoanalytic group therapy, 1954 (Box 51, Folder 259)
      - "A psychogalvanic study of affect states intentionally aroused by imagination" [notes and draft], Circa 1927 (Box 52, Folder 260)
      - Psychopathology
        - Draft, 1931 (Box 52, Folder 261)
        - Introduction, 1932 (Box 52, Folder 262)
      - Psychophysical relations, 1926 (Box 52, Folder 263)
      - Psychotherapeutic situations [notes], 1934-1935 (Box 52, Folder 264)
      - Psychotherapy
        - Notes, Circa 1929-1930 (Box 52, Folder 265)
        - Drafts 1-3, 1931 (Box 52, Folder 266-268)
        - Additional drafts and notes, 1931, undated (Box 52, Folder 269-270)
        - Typescript, Circa 1931 (Box 52, Folder 271)
      - "Public Relations" [manual for the Lifwynn Foundation]
        - Notes, 1951-1954 (Box 52, Folder 272)
        - Typescript, 1953 (Box 52, Folder 273)
      - Reassessment
        - References, Circa 1970 (Box 52, Folder 274)
        - Material [clippings, reprints, notes], 1966-1972 (Box 52, Folder 275)
        - Notes, Circa 1968-1970 (Box 52, Folder 276)
        - Draft, Circa 1970 (Box 52, Folder 277)
      - "Reflections on Nina Bull's The Body and its Mind: An Introduction to Attitude Psychology " [Bull paper]
        - Draft, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 278)
        - Unused portions, Undated (Box 52, Folder 279-280)
      - "The Religious Attitude", 1934 (Box 52, Folder 281)
      - Rorschach lecture
        - Notes, 1924, undated (Box 52, Folder 282)
        - Typescript, 1924 (Box 52, Folder 283)
      - Scientific Method
        - Notes, 1936-1955 (Box 52, Folder 284)
        - Notes, Circa 1938 (Box 52, Folder 285)
        - Drafts, 1929-1938 (Box 52, Folder 286)
      - "Search for Man's Sanity" [review of book by Alfreda S. Galt and Charles B. Thompson], 1956 (Box 52, Folder 287)
      - "Something's Wrong"
        - Notes, Circa 1940 (Box 53, Folder 288)
        - Draft, 1940 (Box 53, Folder 289)
      - "Studies in Phyloanalysis"
        - Outline, Circa 1932-1933 (Box 53, Folder 290)
        - Summary of seven chapters, Circa 1933 (Box 53, Folder 291)
        - Notes, 1932-1934 (Box 53, Folder 292)
        - Introduction, Circa 1930-1933 (Box 53, Folder 293)
        - Divisions
          - Part I, Circa 1932 (Box 53, Folder 294)
          - Part II, Circa 1932 (Box 53, Folder 295)
          - Part III, drafts 1-6, Circa 1932-1933 (Box 53, Folder 296-297)
          - Part IV
            - Drafts 4 and 6, 1932-1933 (Box 53, Folder 298-299)
            - "Suggestion and hypnosis", Circa 1933 (Box 53, Folder 300)
            - "Sex and sexuality", Circa 1934 (Box 53, Folder 301)
            - "Transference", Circa 1932-1934 (Box 53, Folder 302)
            - "Observation", Circa 1926-1932 (Box 53, Folder 303)
            - "Normal/Neurotic", 1927-1934 (Box 53, Folder 304)
          - Part IV a, drafts 1-3, Circa 1933 (Box 53, Folder 305-306)
          - Part IV b, drafts 1-3, Circa 1933 (Box 53, Folder 307-309)
            - "Misconditioning", 1932 (Box 53, Folder 310)
            - "Internal Attention", 1932 (Box 53, Folder 311)
            - "Motor Concepts", 1932 (Box 53, Folder 312)
            - "Attention", 1932 (Box 53, Folder 313)
          - Part V, drafts 1, 3 and 4, 1932 (Box 54, Folder 314-315)
          - Part VI
            - "Instincts", 1931-1934 (Box 54, Folder 316)
            - "Emotions", 1932-1933 (Box 54, Folder 317)
            - Untitled, Circa 1931-1933 (Box 54, Folder 318)
          - Part VII, "Clinical Material", 1932 (Box 54, Folder 319)
          - Part VIII, 1932 (Box 54, Folder 320)
          - Additional material, "Observations", Circa 1928-1933 (Box 54, Folder 321)
          - Additional notes, "Phyloanalytic method", 1933 (Box 54, Folder 322)
      - "Summary"
        - Notes, Circa 1929 (Box 54, Folder 323)
        - Draft, 1929 (Box 54, Folder 324)
        - Notes, Circa 1933 (Box 54, Folder 325-326)
        - Draft of introduction, 1933 (Box 54, Folder 327)
        - Drafts, part II and III, 1933 (Box 54, Folder 328-329)
        - Typescript, 1933 (Box 54, Folder 330)
        - German translation, two drafts, Circa 1933 (Box 54, Folder 331)
      - "Survey", 1935 (Box 54, Folder 332)
      - Technique [notes and draft], 1967-1968 (Box 54, Folder 333)
      - Techniques [draft], 1928-1929 (Box 54, Folder 334)
      - "Therapy" [notes], 1929 (Box 54, Folder 335)
      - "Transference, psychotherapy and the human dilemma"
        - Abstract [submitted to the American Psychiatric Association], 1953 (Box 54, Folder 336)
        - Typescript, 1953-1954 (Box 54, Folder 337)
      - Value Paper
        - Notes, 1958 (Box 55, Folder 338-339)
        - Outline, 1958 (Box 55, Folder 340)
      - Varying perspectives in psychopathology, 1951 (Box 55, Folder 341)
      - World Peace
        - Notes, 1958-1961 (Box 55, Folder 342)
        - Drafts, 1960-1961 (Box 55, Folder 343)
    - Zürich report
      - Notes, 1929-1953 (Box 55, Folder 344)
      - Typescript, 1929 (Box 55, Folder 345)
    - Untitled, 1923-1931
      - Divisions
        - Different approaches: Psychoanalysis, Psychiatry, Circa 1924-1927 (Box 55, Folder 346-348)
        - "Mechanisms", 1925-1927 (Box 55, Folder 349)
        - "Method, Technique VII", 1925-1927 (Box 55, Folder 350)
        - "Principles"
          - Notes, Circa 1924-1927 (Box 55, Folder 351-352)
          - Draft, Circa 1923-1925 (Box 55, Folder 353)
        - "Psychopathology Principles" (Box 55, Folder 354)
        - "Social Factors" [notes], 1927-1931 (Box 55, Folder 355)
        - "Social Neurosis II" [notes], Circa 1927 (Box 55, Folder 356)
        - "Various Topics VI", Circa 1927-1931 (Box 55, Folder 357)
    - Materials for reviews, 1928 (Box 55, Folder 358)
    - Untitled, 1943 (Box 55, Folder 359)
    - Notes for and sketches of book, 1952-1953 (Box 55, Folder 360-365)
    - Notes for book, 1956 (Box 55, Folder 366-367)
    - Unidentified, 1931-1985, undated (Box 55, Folder 368)
  - Experimental data records
    - Psychogalvanic studies
      - Raw data [description of patterns of psychogalvanic responses to stimuli, and other physiological measures] (Box 56, Folder 369-370)
      - Diagrams of psychogalvanic readings, Circa 1925-1925 (Box 56, Folder 371-372)
      - Tabulated data [psychogalvanic measures summarized by descriptive statistics], Circa 1925-1931 (Box 56, Folder 373)
      - Stimuli [tables of verbal stimuli used in psychogalvanic studies], 1926-1931 (Box 56, Folder 374)
    - Neuroanatomical studies
      - Notes on epilepsy and induced convulsions, Circa 1924 (Box 56, Folder 375-378)
      - Observations of brain vessels [notes and diagrams from frog dissection], 1923-1926 (Box 56, Folder 379-380)
- Clinical Files, 1922-1981, undated; Series IV
  The material in this series consists primarily of patient case notes and case presentations, notes on clinical protocol, research files, course outlines, and minutes of staff meetings deriving from Syz's psychiatric work in several clinics and a private practice. They are organized according to the name of the institution at which they were created. Case material that could not be assigned to a particular institution is at the end of the series.
  The files follow the progression of Syz's career from his earliest work as researcher and practitioner at the Phipps Clinic at Johns Hopkins University through his practice in New York City at the New York Hospital and the New York State Hospital. The detailed notes Syz took during staff conferences from 1931 to 1961 provide a participant's perspective on debates taking place in psychiatry in a circuit of major New York psychiatric institutions. These transcripts can be supplemented by notes specifying guidelines for client interviews, treatment, and in some cases the case notes themselves. The files also include class instruction notes from his university teaching and further Rorschach research at the Lifwynn Foundation. See Syz's paper "An experiment in inclusive psychotherapy," (1954) in Series III for a report on how his work at the foundation influenced his psychotherapeutic practice. Series III includes other papers based on clinical research. Some of the relevant case materials are restricted.
  - Johns Hopkins Hospital, Henry Phipps Psychiatric Clinic
    - Notes on brain anatomy, 1922 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Clinical interviews and notes, 1924-1929 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Case records of patients receiving Rorschach tests, 1923-1924 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Psychophysiological experiments
      box 42, folder 1-3
    - Rorschach records, 1922-1926 (Box 57, Folder 4-8)
    - Class instruction notes, 1922-1926 (Box 57, Folder 9-11)
  - New York State Psychiatric Institute
    - Notes from staff conferences, 1934-1935 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Case notes and presentations, 1931-1936 (Box 57, Folder 13)
  - Cornell University Medical College
    - Class instruction notes, 1931-1935, undated (Box 57, Folder 14-15)
    - Description of clinical procedures, 1929-1956 (Box 57, Folder 16-18)
  - New York Hospital
    - Cornell Clinic case notes, 1930-1954 (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - Payne Whitney Clinic notes on staff conferences and case presentations (Box 58, Folder 20-28)
  - Lifwynn Foundation
    - Rorschach records
      - A-H, 1937 (Box 58, Folder 29)
      - J-T, 1937 (Box 58, Folder 30)
  - Unidentified
    - Case notes, 1931-1952 (Box 58, Folder 31)
    - Clinical procedures, 1938-1958 (Box 58, Folder 32-33)
    - Notes on Rorschach test, Circa 1917-1980 (Box 58, Folder 34)
    - References for Rorschach tests, 1933-1981 (Box 58, Folder 35)
- Lifwynn Foundation Files, 1912-1988, undated; Series V